{
    "questions" : [
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "34_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Sir, I'll help you with your order. What kind of ice cream would you like?\nMan : One strawberry flavor and one banana flavor, please.",
            "correctAnswer" : "② ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "34_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Honey, do you want me to put the sweater in the closet drawer?\nWoman : no Please hang it on the upper hanger.",
            "correctAnswer" : "① ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "3. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  약속이 있는지 몰랐구나.",
            "option_2"      : "②  좀 자고 나서 모임에 갈까 해.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이번 모임에는 꼭 나가려고 했거든.",
            "option_4"      : "④  안 와서 무슨 일이 있는 줄 알았어.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Why didn't you come to the meeting yesterday?\nWoman : I lay in bed for a while, but I fell asleep without realizing it.\nMan : I was going to go out for this meeting.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  안 와서 무슨 일이 있는 줄 알았어.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },        
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "4. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  일하는 곳이 마음에 안 드네요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  그럼 이제 일하느라 바빠지겠네요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  곧 일자리를 구할 수 있을 거예요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  내일 저랑 같이 일자리를 찾아봐요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I heard you got a job?\nMan : There's a place I like, so I decided to work from tomorrow.\nWoman : Then you'll be busy working now.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  그럼 이제 일하느라 바빠지겠네요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "5. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  그럼 소금을 갖다 주세요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  설렁탕이 뜨거우니까 조심하십시오.",
            "option_3"      : "③  설렁탕이 싱거우세요?갖다 드릴게요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  소금 없어도 돼요?필요하시면 말씀하세요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Seolleongtang is here. Enjoy your meal \nMan : (The sound of drinking soup) Aunt, please give me some salt here.\nWoman : Is it okay if I don't have salt? Let me know if you need.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  설렁탕이 싱거우세요?갖다 드릴게요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "6. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  게시판은 확인해 보셨어요?",
            "option_2"      : "②  안내문을 만들어 줄 수 있어요?",
            "option_3"      : "③  그럼 이대로 게시판에 붙일까요?",
            "option_4"      : "④  안내문을 언제쯤 완성할 수 있어요?",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Manager, I've made all the notices to be attached to the bulletin board. \nWoman : Shall we take a look? Well...... that's fine.\nMan : Then should I put it on the bulletin board like this?",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  그럼 이대로 게시판에 붙일까요?",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "7. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  어머니의 무릎 상태",
            "option_2"      : "②  무릎건 강과 나이의 관계",
            "option_3"      : "③  무릎이 아플 때 유의점",
            "option_4"      : "④  어머니의 무릎이 아픈 이유",
            "detail"        : "\n(Conversation between a son in his 30s and a mother in his 60s)\nMan : Mother, how is your knee pain? \nWoman : I was told that it's good to take medicine and walk backwards, so I've been doing it for a few days and my knees have improved a lot.\nMan : That's a relief. But you still have to be careful.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  어머니의 무릎 상태",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "8. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  운동장 개방의 중요성",
            "option_2"      : "②  운동장 이용 시 주의 사항",
            "option_3"      : "③  운동장을 개방하는 시간",
            "option_4"      : "④  운동장을 이용하는 사람들",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Many schools are opening playgrounds these days. So in the evening, you can see a lot of citizens exercising or taking a walk. Throwing trash on the floor or a chair is becoming a problem. You need to think about the people around you and use it cleanly.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  운동장 이용 시 주의 사항",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "9. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  스타킹을 신어야 하는 이유",
            "option_2"      : "②  스타킹에 묻은 먼지 제거 방법",
            "option_3"      : "③  구멍 난 스타킹을 활용하는 방법",
            "option_4"      : "④  스타킹에 자주 구멍이 나는 이유",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Do you care if there's dust build up under an unreachable bed or sofa? In that case, put stockings on the hanger and wipe it. It's easy to get rid of even the smallest amount of dust. You often get a hole when you wear stockings. Don't throw away these holed stockings and use them again.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  구멍 난 스타킹을 활용하는 방법",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "10. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  사고 처리 상황",
            "option_2"      : "②  사고 예방 대책",
            "option_3"      : "③  사고 대처 방법",
            "option_4"      : "④  사고 발생 원인",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : The water pipe exploded at the intersection of Hankook University in the morning. Due to this accident, the water supply has not been supplied to the area for three hours, so the residents are experiencing inconvenience. The current burst is blocked and the water no longer comes out. It is said that you will be able to supply the water soon after the work of changing the water pipe. I think local residents will have to wait a little longer.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  사고 처리 상황",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "11. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  백화점은 오늘까지 세일을 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  두 사람은 아침 일찍 백화점에 왔다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  지난번 세일 때는 물건이 많지 않았다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자는 마음에 드는 옷을 살 수 없었다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : It's a department store sale, but there aren't many items. Today is the first day.......\nMan : I know. I didn't do that last time on sale, but is it because I came in the evening?\nWoman : I should have come earlier. All the clothes I like are left in a large size.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  여자는 마음에 드는 옷을 살 수 없었다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "12. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  카메라의 색깔은 검은색이다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  관리사무소는 식당 옆에 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  카메라 가방에는 사진이 두 장 들어 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  카메라를 본 사람은 관리사무소에 가면 된다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I'm looking for a camera. A park user lost his white camera at a restaurant in the park around 2 p.m. today. The camera is a product from Korea Electronics and is in a black bag. It is said that precious photo files are stored on the camera. If you are looking at the camera or keeping it, please come to the management office next to the front door.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  카메라를 본 사람은 관리사무소에 가면 된다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "13. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 선수는 중학교 때 운동선수가 되었다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 선수는 경기에서 좋은 기록을 세웠다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 선수는 계속 올림픽에 도전할 것이다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 선수는 이번 올림픽에 처음 출전하였다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMen : Our athlete Lee Jung-mi, we have finished our long career after this Olympics. Lee Jung-mi, who started her career in middle school, left a record of participating in the Olympics six times. Although he did not perform well in the Olympics, Lee Jung-mi's challenging spirit is very impressive to the people.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  이 선수는 중학교 때 운동선수가 되었다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "14. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  요즘 몸에 좋은 만두가 많이 나왔다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  사서 먹는 만두의 모양이 더 예쁘다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  만두를 직접 만들어서 먹는 것이 좋다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  만두는 여러 가지 재료로 만들어야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Wow! That sounds delicious The shape is so pretty, too. But isn't it hard to make dumplings yourself? It's more convenient for me to buy and eat.......\nMan : That's true, but if I make it myself, I can make it with my favorite ingredients and it's better for my body, wouldn't it?",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  만두를 직접 만들어서 먹는 것이 좋다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 남자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "15. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  광고지를 길에 버리면 안 된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  광고지가 도움이 될 때가 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  길에서 주는 광고지는 광고 효과가 크다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  좋은 정보가 있는 광고지를 만들어야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I don't know why they distribute these flyers. Most people don't look at it and just throw it away. There's not much advertising effect, and I think it's a waste. \nMan : Is that so?( I'm a little puzzled and lightly refuted) I'm going to receive it. I sometimes get information from there. It's a pity that it's not there when I need it again......",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  광고지가 도움이 될 때가 있다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "16. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  길고양이에게 먹이를 주면 안 된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  길고양이에게 주인을 찾아 줘야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  길고양이는 먹이를 안 줘도 많아질 것이다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  길고양이 때문에 생활이 불편해지는 건 아니다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There are a lot of stray cats in my neighborhood these days. It don't have an owner, and I'm sorry, so I want to feed it.\nMan : But if you keep feeding them, the number of stray cats will increase. If the number of cats increases, won't there be more accidents caused by cats? I can't even sleep at night because of the sound of crying.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  길고양이에게 먹이를 주면 안 된다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "17. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  상담을 받을 때는 전문가를 찾아가야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  상담으로 고민을 해결하려면 시간이 걸린다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  확실한 해결 방법을 상담에서 얻을 수 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  고민을 이야기하기만 해도 상담의 효과가 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There are a lot of people looking for a professional to get counseling these days. Some people say that they just wasted their time because they didn't hear a clear solution even after receiving a consultation.\nMan : Of course, it will also be important to find a definitive solution through counseling. However, I think the effect of counseling is enough just to feel that someone can solve their concerns and that there is someone who listens to them well.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  고민을 이야기하기만 해도 상담의 효과가 있다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "18. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  표를 받는다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  마실 것을 산다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  좌석을 확인한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  공연장 입구로 간다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Come quickly. What time does our performance start?\nMan : It starts at 7 o'clock, so I still have some time.\nWoman : (Like looking at the clock, after a while) That's right. But where are our seats? Man: You have to get a ticket to know the seat.\nWoman : Then let's go quickly and get the ticket first.\nMan : I'll get the tickets, so you go get something to drink.\nWoman : Yes. Then let's meet at the entrance of the concert hall a little later.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  마실 것을 산다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "19. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  계산을 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  카드를 만든다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  가방을 골라 준다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  포인트를 적립해 준다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Sir, do you want this red bag?\nMan : Yes, give me that one.\nWoman : I got it. By the way, do you have a customer card in our store? If you give it to me, I will earn points for you.\nMan : I don't have a card. Does it take a long time to make?\nWoman : no It will be soon I'll pay first and make it for you.\nMan : (Thinking) Well....... It's OK I'll make the card next time.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  계산을 한다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "20. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  고객 만족도를 조사한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  설문지의 질문을 만든다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  과장님에게 보고하러 간다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  설문 조사 결과를 정리한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Jeong-soo, I've summarized the results of the customer satisfaction survey, so please take a look. I think something is lacking.\nMan : (after a while) um....... The female customer satisfaction part is a bit like that. \nWoman : Right? I need to do one more survey.\nMan : Well, the questionnaire last time seemed to lack the number of questions. \nWoman : This time, let's make a few more questions and investigate. First, I will report this situation to the manager.\nMan : Yes. Then I'll make a question to enter the questionnaire. Please review the contents later.\nWoman : OK",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  과장님에게 보고하러 간다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "21. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 식당의 메뉴는 10년 동안 변하지 않았다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 식당의 음식 맛은 전보다 훨씬 좋아졌다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 여자의 아이는 이 집의 칼국수를 좋아한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 여자를 식당에 처음 데리고 온 사람은 부모님이다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : 'Delicious T V' Today, I'm at a collection of sword soup in Seoul, which boasts a 50-year tradition. Even though it's before lunch time, the line is already long.( After a while) I think all the family members are here, do you come to this house often?\nWoman : Yes. This house hasn't raised its price for 10 years. It's hard to go somewhere at this price and have a lunch like this. And I didn't have a menu that my daughter liked before, but I had pork cutlet for a while, so my child likes it too.\nMan : You're a regular. Then when did you first come to this restaurant?\nWoman : I've been with my parents since I was young. But even then and now, the taste of the food remains the same.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  이 여자를 식당에 처음 데리고 온 사람은 부모님이다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "22.  남자는 누구인지 고르십시오 ",
            "option_1"      : "①  기자",
            "option_2"      : "②  가게 주인",
            "option_3"      : "③  손님",
            "option_4"      : "④  전문 요리사",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : 'Delicious T V' Today, I'm at a collection of sword soup in Seoul, which boasts a 50-year tradition. Even though it's before lunch time, the line is already long.( After a while) I think all the family members are here, do you come to this house often?\nWoman : Yes. This house hasn't raised its price for 10 years. It's hard to go somewhere at this price and have a lunch like this. And I didn't have a menu that my daughter liked before, but I had pork cutlet for a while, so my child likes it too.\nMan : You're a regular. Then when did you first come to this restaurant?\nWoman : I've been with my parents since I was young. But even then and now, the taste of the food remains the same.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  기자",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자는 무엇을 하고 있는지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  기능의 원리를 밝히고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  기능의 효과에 대해 묻고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  기능의 장점에 대해 설명하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  기능을 사용해 본 경험을 말하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I have some good news for novice drivers. Let's listen to the news with Kim Cheol-soo, a researcher of Hankook Motor.\nMan : Many drivers have difficulty parking. Especially for novice drivers. The function developed this time is to solve these concerns. If you stop the car in front of the parking space and press the button, it will be parked automatically. There is no problem if the space between the car and the car is narrow. Many people are inquiring these days because the parking problem is easily solved with the push of a button.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  기능의 장점에 대해 설명하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "24. 이 기능을 만든 이유를 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  운전자들의 불만이 많아서",
            "option_2"      : "②  초보 운전자들이 줄어들어서",
            "option_3"      : "③  주차의 어려움을 해결하기 위해",
            "option_4"      : "④  주차장을 다양하게 활용하기 위해",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I have some good news for novice drivers. Let's listen to the news with Kim Cheol-soo, a researcher of Hankook Motor.\nMan : Many drivers have difficulty parking. Especially for novice drivers. The function developed this time is to solve these concerns. If you stop the car in front of the parking space and press the button, it will be parked automatically. There is no problem if the space between the car and the car is narrow. Many people are inquiring these days because the parking problem is easily solved with the push of a button.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  주차의 어려움을 해결하기 위해",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "25. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  대화를 할 때는 분명한 목적이 있어야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  수다와 잡담은 상대와 친해지기 위한 방법이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  대화 방법은 상대가 누구냐에 따라 달라진다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  상대와 공통점이 있을 때 수다와 잡담을 하게 된다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I often think of casual conversations in everyday life as useless chat or small talk. I think of it as a story to pass the time. But one psychologist said such conversations were also meaningful. “How have you been?”, “Do you like that song?” The same light conversation is actually 'I want to be close', 'I want to know about the other one.' It means Through those questions, you are looking for something in common with yourself and others. Because when there is something similar to me, we quickly feel intimacy. The light conversation you have in your daily life seems just meaningless, but it's actually an effort to get along with the other person.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  수다와 잡담은 상대와 친해지기 위한 방법이다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "26. 여자가 제시한 주장의 근거로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  관련 서적",
            "option_2"      : "②  외국의 사례",
            "option_3"      : "③  자신의 경험",
            "option_4"      : "④  전문가의 의견",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I often think of casual conversations in everyday life as useless chat or small talk. I think of it as a story to pass the time. But one psychologist said such conversations were also meaningful. “How have you been?”, “Do you like that song?” The same light conversation is actually 'I want to be close', 'I want to know about the other one.' It means Through those questions, you are looking for something in common with yourself and others. Because when there is something similar to me, we quickly feel intimacy. The light conversation you have in your daily life seems just meaningless, but it's actually an effort to get along with the other person.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  전문가의 의견",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "27. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  회사마다 옷에 대한 기준이 다르다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  일을 할 때 편한 옷을 입는 것이 좋다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  옷을 통해 상대방에게 믿음을 주어야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  옷을 입을 때는 직업의 특성을 고려해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWomen : There are many companies that have become free to dress these days. They say you can wear jeans or a T-shirt to work instead of a suit, but I think the idea will be of great help to a computer company or design company that is important. Because if you work in a comfortable atmosphere, you can feel free.\nMan : The hard atmosphere of the company will change a little. I think an individual's personality can also be respected. However, for office workers who have to deal with customers often, it would be difficult to dress too comfortably. Depending on the other person, you can accept that light clothes are not polite. Wouldn't the meaning of clothes be different for each job?",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  일을 할 때 편한 옷을 입는 것이 좋다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "28. 남자의 생각이나 태도로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자의 생각을 칭찬하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자의 결정을 받아들이고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자의 의견에 대해 궁금해하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자의 말에 부분적으로 동의하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWomen : There are many companies that have become free to dress these days. They say you can wear jeans or a T-shirt to work instead of a suit, but I think the idea will be of great help to a computer company or design company that is important. Because if you work in a comfortable atmosphere, you can feel free.\nMan : The hard atmosphere of the company will change a little. I think an individual's personality can also be respected. However, for office workers who have to deal with customers often, it would be difficult to dress too comfortably. Depending on the other person, you can accept that light clothes are not polite. Wouldn't the meaning of clothes be different for each job?",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  여자의 말에 부분적으로 동의하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "29. 이 뉴스의 제목으로 가장 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  유치원의 변화,교사들 팔 걷어붙여",
            "option_2"      : "②  월요일 특별 수업,학부모의 참여 늘어",
            "option_3"      : "③  이야기꾼 할머니,유치원에서 제2의 인생 시작해",
            "option_4"      : "④  노인 일자리 사업,정부의 관심에서 점점 멀어져",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : It is said that there is a special teacher in a kindergarten in Inju. Reporter Kim Soo-jin will deliver this news.\nWomen : Every Monday, you can meet a special teacher at this kindergarten. You're a 'storyteller's grandmother teacher who is taking the 'old story' class, and it's said that it's popular because it's very fun to tell children about old stories. This special teacher is working through the 'Serly Jobs Program' conducted by the government, and it is said that it is very rewarding to teach children. It is said that the elderly who came to work again through this program also like it, and the kindergarten children and parents are well received. This is Soo-jin Kim from KBC News.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  이야기꾼 할머니,유치원에서 제2의 인생 시작해",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "30. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  부모님들이 일일 선생님으로 유치원에 나온다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  옛날이야기를 들려주는 직업이 인기를 끌고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  할머니 선생님은 이 유치원에서 가장 오래 가르쳤다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 유치원에서는 월요일마다 ‘옛날이야기’수업을 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : It is said that there is a special teacher in a kindergarten in Inju. Reporter Kim Soo-jin will deliver this news.\nWomen : Every Monday, you can meet a special teacher at this kindergarten. You're a 'storyteller's grandmother teacher who is taking the 'old story' class, and it's said that it's popular because it's very fun to tell children about old stories. This special teacher is working through the 'Serly Jobs Program' conducted by the government, and it is said that it is very rewarding to teach children. It is said that the elderly who came to work again through this program also like it, and the kindergarten children and parents are well received. This is Soo-jin Kim from KBC News.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  이 유치원에서는 월요일마다 ‘옛날이야기’수업을 한다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        }
    ]
}
